A world light-years beyond your imagination.
Krull is a action, adventure, fantasy film directed by Peter Yates.
A prince and a fellowship of companions set out to rescue his bride from a
fortress of alien invaders who have arrived on their home planet.
Prince Colwyn, played by Ken Marshall.
Lyssa, played by Lysette Anthony.
Ynyr, played by Freddie Jones.
Widow of the Web, played by Francesca Annis.
Torquil, played by Alun Armstrong.
Ergo, played by David Battley.
Krull is a 1983 British science fantasy adventure film directed by
Peter Yates and distributed by Columbia Pictures.
It stars Ken Marshall, Lysette Anthony, Freddie Jones,
Francesca Annis, David Battley and Alun Armstrong.
Liam Neeson and Robbie Coltrane, still early in their
film careers, appear in supporting roles.
The story follows Prince Colwyn (Marshall) and a fellowship of companions who set out to rescue his bride,
Princess Lyssa (Anthony), from a fortress of alien invaders who have arrived on their home planet.
Development on the film began in 1980, when Columbia Pictures President Frank
Price gave producer Ron Silverman the idea to produce a fantasy film.
Krull was shot in England at Pinewood Studios and
on-location in Italy and Spain.
Nick Maley designed the creature and prosthetic makeup effects seen in the film.
The film score was composed by James Horner and
performed by the London Symphony Orchestra.
Krull was released in the United States on July 29, 1983, and
in the United Kingdom later that December.
The film was a box-office bomb upon release, and critical opinion
has been mixed, both upon release and in retrospect.
Reviewers have highlighted its visual effects and soundtrack, while others
have criticized its plot as being derivative and nonsensical.
In the years since its release, the film has developed a cult following.
The film explores themes of kingdom, dead body,
magical object, fortress, swashbuckler.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking.